<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<concept id="ap-userinterface">
    <title>User Interface</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>
                <xref href="#instances">Flow Instances Page</xref>
            </p>
            <p>
                <xref href="#flowCatalog">Flow Catalog Page</xref>
            </p>
            <p>
                <xref href="#disableFlow">Enable/Disable Flow</xref>
            </p>
            <p>
                <xref href="#instanceDetails">Flow Instance Details Page</xref>
            </p>
            <p>
                <xref href="#scopingPanel">Scoping Panel</xref>
            </p>

        </section>
        <section id="instances">
            <title>Flow Instances Page</title>

            <p>
                The <b>Flow Automation</b> user interface main page displays the <b>Flow Instances</b> table.
                <image href="/resources/images/fa/Flow_Automation.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                The table displays the following columns:
                <ul class="elHelpLib-Concept-ul">
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>Name</b>: Flow name.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>Flow</b>: Description of the flow.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>User-Tasks</b>: The outstanding number of user-tasks.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>State</b>: Current phase of the flow execution.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>Summary Report</b>: Live Status of the flow instance
                            indicating where it is, and what is happening.
                            It is always based on what the flow designer sets during design time.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>Start Time</b>: Time at which the flow instance started.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>End Time</b>: Time at which the flow instance finished.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>Duration</b>: Duration of flow execution (Optional column, it
                            must be selected in the <i>Table Settings</i> to be displayed).
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>Started By</b>: Name of user who started the flow.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>Flow Version</b>: The version of the flow that was in use at
                            the time the flow instance was
                            started.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p>
                By default, only the instances that were started by the current user will be displayed in the table. To
                display all flow
                instances for all users, toggle the <b>My Flow Instances</b> button at the top of the table.
            </p>

            <p>
                The <b>Summary</b> shows how many flow instances are in the setup, executing, or executed
                state.
            </p>
            <p>
                <image height="80px" width="80px" href="/resources/images/stopButtonInstancesPage.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                The flow instances in Executing Phase can be stopped by clicking the <b>Stop</b> button in the action
                bar. The <b>Stop</b> button appears in the action bar only when selecting the flow instance which is in
                the Executing Phase. This feature should be used with caution, as it is not a graceful cancel of the
                flow instance and causes the executing instance to stop forcibly.
            </p>
            <p>
                <image height="80px" width="80px" href="/resources/images/deleteButtonInstancesPage.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                The flow instances in Final State can be deleted by clicking the <b>Delete Instance</b> button in the action
                bar. The <b>Delete Instance</b> button appears in the action bar only when selecting a flow instance which is in
                a Final State. This feature should be used with caution, as after deletion of the instance,
                you won't be able to review the result or troubleshoot the flow further.
            </p>
            <p>
                <image height="80px" width="80px" href="/resources/images/discard-flow.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                The flow instances in Setup State can be deleted by clicking the <b>Discard Setup</b> button in the action
                bar. The <b>Discard Setup</b> button appears in the action bar only when selecting a flow instance which is in
                a Setup State. This feature should be used with caution, as after discard of the instance,
                you won't be able to view it or troubleshoot the flow further.
            </p>

        </section>
        <section id="flowCatalog">
            <title>Flow Catalog Page</title>
            <image href="/resources/images/fa/FlowCatalogHiperlink.png"/>
            <p>
                Click <b>View Flow Catalog</b> hyperlink from the Flow Automation page to navigate to the flow catalog
                page.
            </p>
            <image href="/resources/images/fa/Flow_Catalog.png"/>
            <p>
                The flows table displays a list of all imported flows with the following columns:
                <ul class="elHelpLib-Concept-ul">
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>Name</b>: Flow name.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>Description</b>: Description of the flow.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>Version</b>: Flow version.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p"><b>Imported By</b>: Name of the user who imported the flow.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                </ul>
                When a flow is selected, the <b>Documentation Summary</b> details are displayed in the right panel.
            </p>
            <image href="/resources/images/fa/FlowCatalogDocumentation.png"/>
            <p>
                <b>Note:</b>
                When a new version of an existing flow is imported, the flow is updated to the new version. Flow
                versions are
                in the format: XX.YY.ZZ. The imported flow version must be a higher version than the existing flow
                version or an error
                is displayed. Instances already running with any previous versions of the flow will continue to execute.
                Subsequent flow instances started will be with the new version.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="disableFlow">
            <title>Disable/Enable a Flow</title>

            <p>
                When a flow is imported, it is automatically enabled.
                Refer to <xref type="concept" href="/tutorials/importFlow.xml#1">Import a Flow</xref> for details on how
                to import a flow.
            </p>

            <p>
                When an imported flow is selected, you can choose to <b>Enable</b> or <b>Disable</b> that particular
                flow.
            </p>

            <p>
                Click <b>Enable</b> to enable a flow. This allows new flow instances to start.
            </p>

            <p>
                Click <b>Disable</b> to disable a flow. New flow instances cannot be started when a flow is disabled.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="instanceDetails">
            <title>Flow Instance Details Page</title>
            <p>
                The <b>Flow Instance Details</b> page displays the
                <b>Flow Instance Summary Panel.</b>
                <image href="/resources/images/fa/Flow_Instance_Details.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                This panel displays the following:
                <ul class="elHelpLib-Concept-ul">
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p">
                            <b>State:</b>
                            The following states are supported: <b>Setup</b>, <b>Executing</b> and
                            <b>Executed</b>
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p">
                            <b>Start Time:</b>
                            Time the flow instance started
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p">
                            <b>End Time:</b>
                            Time the flow instance finished
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p">
                            <b>Started By:</b>
                            Name of user who started the instance
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                        <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p">
                            <b>Summary Report:</b>
                            Live Status of the flow instance indicating where it is, and what is happening. It is always
                            based on what the flow designer sets during design time.
                        </p>
                    </li>

                </ul>
            </p>

            <u>
                <b>Report Tab</b>
            </u>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/ReportTab.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                The <b>Report</b> tab contains two different views:
            </p>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/ReportTabButtons.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Execution</b>
                - This displays the details of executing and executed flow instances.
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Setup</b>
                - This displays the data that was entered during the Setup Phase.
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Note:</b>
                The Report tab is not displayed when the flow instance is in the Setup Phase.
            </p>
            <p>
                The execution view is selected by default and the views can be alternated through use of the
                corresponding buttons shown on the Report tab
            </p>
            <p>
                The execution content is defined in the flow during flow design. This determines what is displayed in
                the
                execution view of the Report tab.
                If a report is not defined for a flow, no report details are displayed.
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Report Table</b>
            </p>
            <p>
                The <b>Report</b> table is shown in the execution view and shows the report results in tabular format.
                The report table can be sorted and filtered.
            </p>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/report_table.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                The <b>Report</b> provides an action framework. When the action framework is activated,
                it is possible to select table rows, as in the image below.
            </p>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/action-framework/selected2rows.jpg"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Filtering Report Table</b>
            </p>
            <p>
                Filtering can be based on individual columns, or on all the columns.
                By default the filtering displays all columns. So whatever text typed is searched in
                all the columns of the table.
                User can also select individual columns if they want to filter on a specific column.
            </p>
            <p>
                When the action framework is activated and rows are selected,
                if the data is filtered then the selected rows will be cleared. This can be seen in the image below.
            </p>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/action-framework/filterWillUnselectRow.jpg"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Setup Data</b>
            </p>
            <p>
                Click the <b>Setup</b> button to display the data selected during the Setup Phase.
            </p>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/SampleSetupData.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                The Setup Configuration can be exported in a file using the <b>Export</b> button.
            </p>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/exportSetupConfig.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                This file can be used to instantiate the same flow with the same configuration by selecting the file input option during the Choose Setup user-task.
            </p>
            <p>
                The Setup Configuration is only available for flows which have a Setup Phase and can only be exported from the Review and Confirm stage and onwards.
                The other exportable option is the execution Report and is only available from the Execution Phase and onwards.
            </p>

            <u>
                <b>User-Tasks Tab</b>
            </u>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/UserTasksTab.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>The <b>User-Tasks</b> tab contains details of user-tasks required to execute an instance.
            </p>
            <p>The left panel displays a list of flow instance user-tasks. The right panel displays a user-task form.
            </p>
            <p>User-tasks are displayed differently in the Setup Phase and Execution Phase.</p>
            <p>In the Setup Phase tasks are displayed and must be completed in sequential order.</p>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/setupusertask.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>The final task in the Setup Phase is the <b>Review and Confirm Execute</b> task.
                This task allows you to review all the data input before executing the flow instance.
            </p>
            <p>The following buttons are displayed for the Setup Phase:</p>
            <ul class="elHelpLib-Concept-ul">
                <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                    <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p">
                        <b>Continue:</b>
                        Completes the current user-task and brings you to the next task.
                        This button is not available for the <b>Review and Confirm Execute</b> task.
                    </p>
                    <p>The button will be disabled when there is a scroll bar on the user-task and will only enable once the user scrolls to the bottom and the whole user-task content has been viewed.</p>
                </li>
                <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                    <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p">
                        <b>Execute:</b>
                        Executes the user-tasks. This button is only available in the <b>Review and Confirm Execute</b> task.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                    <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p">
                        <b>Discard Setup:</b>
                        Discards the setup of the flow instance.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li class="elHelpLib-Concept-li">
                    <p class="elHelpLib-Concept-p">
                        <b>Restart:</b>
                        Discards currently running flow instance execution, and restarts a new instance.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>When selecting the <b>Execute</b> button the Confirm Execution dialog box will open.
                From here, the execution of the flow can either be confirmed by again selecting <b>Execute</b>
                or cancelled by selecting the <b>Cancel</b> button.
            </p>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/confirmExecution.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>In the Execution Phase, user-tasks can be completed in any order.</p>
            <p>In case of a multi-instance flow, when there are grouped user-tasks, they are displayed grouped by their names in separate accordions.</p>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/groupedUsertasks.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>The <b>Submit</b> button is displayed for the Execution Phase. This button completes the current user
                task.
            </p>
            <p>In the case of a multi instance flow, if there is more than one user-task in a group, the user has the option to select the
                <b>Submit to multiple tasks</b> button for completion simultaneously.Selecting this will open the Submit to Multiple tasks dialog box.</p>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/submitMultipleUsertasks.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                In this dialog box, either individual instances can be selected or the <b>Select All</b> button can be used to select all instances.
                All selected instances can also be cleared by using the <b>Select None</b> button.
            </p>
            <p>
                Once selected, instances can be submitted via the <b>Submit</b> button or the the <b>Cancel</b> button can be selected to close the dialog box.
            </p>
            <u>
                <b>Process Diagram Tab</b>
            </u>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/ProcessDiagramTab.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                The <b>Process Diagram</b> tab contains two different views.
            </p>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/ProcessDiagramButton.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Definition:</b>
                - This displays the flow diagram details.
                <fig>
                    <title></title>
                    <image href="resources/images/DefinitionDiagram.png"/>
                </fig>
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Activity:</b>
                - This dynamically displays the executed path of the different phases of the flow.
                <fig>
                    <title></title>
                    <image href="resources/images/ActivityDiagram.png"/>
                </fig>
            </p>

            <u>
                <b>Events Tab</b>
            </u>
            <p>
                The <b>Events tab</b> displays events that are logged during the execution of the flow instance -
            </p>
            <p>
                <image href="resources/images/eventsTab.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                Events can be filtered using the start time, end time and/or through the use of the severity buttons which are displayed as icons for either Error, Warning or Info.
                The data may also be refreshed at any time by clicking the <b>Refresh Button</b>.
                This will also clear all currently applied filters.
            </p>
            <p>
                When an event is clicked it displays details of that event in the right panel
            </p>
            <p>
                <image href="resources/images/eventDetails.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                When the <b>Filter Button</b> is clicked it displays all the available filters in the right fly-out panel.
            </p>
            <p>
                <image href="resources/images/filterButton.png"/>
            </p>
            <p>
                From this panel, the same Date/time and Severity filters are available as well as two other filters that
                operate on the Resource and Message Synopsis columns of the Events Table.
            </p>
            <p>
                <image href="resources/images/eventsFilterFlyout.png"/>
            </p>
            <u>
                <b>Topology Selection</b>
            </u>
            <p>During the Setup Phase, some flow instances may require Topology selection.
            </p>
            <p>Click <b>Add Topology Data</b> to select the required objects from the <b>Add Network
                Objects
            </b> scoping panel.
            </p>
            <p>Nodes and Collections can be selected from the scoping panel, and the selected objects are displayed in
                table format.
            </p>
            <p>The <b>Node Name</b>, <b>NeType</b>, and the <b>Collection Name</b> are displayed for the selected nodes.
            </p>
            <p>
                <image href="/resources/images/nodeSelectedTable.png"/>
            </p>

            <p>Click the delete icon
                <image href="resources/images/deleteIcon.png" alt="delete Icon"/>
                to delete a selected object
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="scopingPanel">
            <title>Scoping Panel</title>
            <p>The <b>Scoping Panel</b> is used to select network objects during the user-task Setup Phase for flow
                instances that require topology selection.
            </p>
            <image href="/resources/images/scopingPanel.png"/>
            <p>Click <b>Add Topology Data</b> in the <b>User-Task</b> tab, on the <b>Instance Details</b> page, to
                access the <b>Scoping Panel</b>.
            </p>
            <p>Click <b>Add Topology Data</b> to display/hide the <b>Scoping Panel</b>.
            </p>
            <p>The <b>Scoping Panel</b> is displayed on the right of the UI with the <b>Add Network Objects</b> heading.
            </p>
            <p>The <b>Scoping Panel</b> contains the following tabs:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <u>Topology</u>
                    - This allows nodes and subnetworks to be selected directly from the network topology.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <u>Search</u>
                    - This allows nodes and subnetworks to be selected directly from the network topology.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <u>Collections</u>
                    - This allows network objects to be selected via existing collections.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <u>Saved Searches</u>
                    - This allows network objects to be selected via existing saved searches.
                </li>
            </ul>

            <p>Note the following <b>Scoping Panel</b> behaviours:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    Items selected in the <b>Scoping Panel</b> tabs are retained when navigating between the tabs.
                </li>
                <li>
                    The <b>Topology</b> tab only displays supported nodes. This tab may be empty if it contains
                    no supported nodes.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Subnetworks are always displayed in the <b>Topology</b> tab.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Selecting a subnetwork in the <b>Topology</b> tab displays the subnetwork.
                    It <b>will not</b> display the nodes beneath it or the nested subnetwork nodes contained in the
                    subnetwork.
                    Nested subnetworks must be selected to view the nodes they contain.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Selecting the <b>Add</b> button in a <b>Scoping Panel</b> tab, adds the selected objects
                    to the Flow Instance and closes the <b>Scoping Panel</b>.
                </li>
            </ul>

            <sectiondiv id="Topology">
                <p>
                    <b>
                        <u>Topology Tab</u>
                    </b>
                </p>
                <p>
                    The <b>Topology</b> tab is the default tab.
                    <fig>
                        <title></title>
                        <image href="resources/images/topologyTab.png"/>
                    </fig>
                </p>
                <p>
                    The <b>Topology</b> tab contains the <b>Subnetworks</b> and the <b>All other nodes</b> items. Nodes
                    are found
                    under the <b>All other nodes</b> item unless they are added beneath a Subnetwork.
                </p>
                <p>Subnetworks are displayed by the globe icon
                    <image href="resources/images/globe.png"/>
                </p>
                <p>Nodes are displayed by the base station icon
                    <image href="resources/images/baseStation.png"/>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <b>All other nodes</b>
                    are displayed by the folder icon
                    <image href="resources/images/folder.png"/>
                </p>
                <p>Synched nodes are displayed by the following icon
                    <image href="resources/images/synched.png"/>
                </p>
                <p>Unsynched nodes are displayed by the following icon
                    <image href="resources/images/unsynched.png"/>
                </p>
            </sectiondiv>
            <sectiondiv id="Search">
                <p>
                    <b>
                        <u>Search Tab</u>
                    </b>
                </p>
                <p>
                    The <b>Search</b> tab allows you to search for nodes based on supported managed object names, node
                    names, collection names, and saved search names.
                    Select the desired node(s) and click <b>Add</b> to add the node(s) in the <b>Ungrouped objects</b> table.
                    <fig>
                        <title></title>
                        <image href="resources/images/searchTab.png"/>
                    </fig>
                </p>
                <p>The following managed object types are supported:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        NetworkElement
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        SubNetwork
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        ManagedElement
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        MeContext
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </sectiondiv>
            <sectiondiv id="Collections">
                <p>
                    <b>
                        <u>Collections Tab</u>
                    </b>
                </p>
                <p>
                    The
                    <b>Collection</b>
                    tab allows you to select required Collection.
                    <fig>
                        <title></title>
                        <image href="resources/images/collectionsTab.png"/>
                    </fig>
                </p>
                <p>The collections displayed can be filtered by:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <b>Name</b>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>Visibility</b>
                        (Public, Private, or All)
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>Favorites</b>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </sectiondiv>
            <sectiondiv id="SavedSearches">
                <p>
                    <b>
                        <u>Saved Searches Tab</u>
                    </b>
                </p>
                <p>
                    The
                    <b>Saved Searches</b>
                    tab allows you to select required Saved Seaches.
                    <fig>
                        <title></title>
                        <image href="resources/images/savedSearchesTab.png"/>
                    </fig>
                </p>
                <p>The Saved Searches displayed can be filtered by:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <b>Name</b>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>Visibility</b>
                        (Public, Private, or All)
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>Favorites</b>
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p>
                    <b>Note:</b>
                    If the search contains a large number of results, the
                    application might become unresponsive. Try to refine your search before adding nodes.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <b>Note: </b>
                    Regardless of the number of nodes in a collection. FA will only display the first 250. This is also noted on the UI as displayed below.
                    <fig>
                        <title></title>
                        <image href="resources/images/collectionLimit.png"/>
                    </fig>
                </p>
            </sectiondiv>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
